Finding Aid for The Robert H. Davis Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
The Robert H. Davis Papers
Undated
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0713
2.95 linear_feet
Biography
Robert H. Davis, 1939-2007 received a BA from Illinois College and an MA, PhD from Vanderbilt University. He was a senior member of the History Department, Luther College, Decorah, Iowa, had directed its foreign studies center in Nottingham, England, and both its Latin American and International Studies programs on campus. He was a corresponding member of the Academia Columbiana de Historia (Bogota) and a noted Colombianist. He wrote a seminal work of bibliography entitled the Historical Dictionary of Colombia which is still a highly referenced work on the history and culture of the country.
Scope and Content
These papers consist of the teaching and research of Robert H. Davis a scholar on Colombia and Latin America. Davis graduated from Vanderbilt University with a PhD in 1969 and went on to a career teaching in academia.
- Geographical and Political Research on South America
  - Introduction To The Latin American Republic (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Latin America And The Alliance For Progress (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Compilation Of Study Of Cost Arica (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Mexico Map Analysis (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Influence Of Religion In Central America (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Work On Haiti (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Work On Guatemala (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Class Material On Mexican History (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Paideia Foreign Policy Research (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Letters Awards And University Correspondence With Davis Robert (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Historical Geography Of South America Class Work (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Mexico Review Terms (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Curriculum Vitae Of J. León Helguera And Raymond Leslie (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Game Theory Course Work (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Geographical and Political Research on South America
  - History Of Central America And The USA (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Work On Developing Nations (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Letters Maps And Notes On Central America (Box 2, Folder 17)
- History of South America
  - Bolivia And Spanish Independence (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - History Course Work Class, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - History Of Latin American Republics Class, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Brief Geography And History Of The Bahamas (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - History Of Cuba And The Caribbean Class 1984 Part 1 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - History Of Cuba And The Caribbean Class 1984 Part 2 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - History Of Mexico And Central America Class, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Research on Colombia
  - Post Cards Of Colombia (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Andean America Colombia And Peru: Part 1 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Andean America Colombia And Peru: Part 2 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Andean America Colombia And Peru: Part 3 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Colombian Art And History (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Analysis Of Colombian Congress, 1832-1861 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Descriptive Material On Papaya Colombia (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Colombian Report, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Genealogy Of The Lleras Family Colombia (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Map Of The Republic Of Colombia, July 1986 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Writings On Colombia (Box 4, Folder 35)
- Writings
  - Writings: Bibliography (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Writings: Bibliography (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Writings: Bibliography (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Writings: Bibliography (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Writings: Bibliography (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Writings: Bibliography (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Writings: Bibliography (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Writings: Bibliography (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Writings: Bibliography (Box 5, Folder 44)
- Writings
  - Writings: Bibliography (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Writings: Bibliography (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Writings: Bibliography (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Writings: Bibliography (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Writings: Bibliography (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Writings: Bibliography (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Writings: Bibliography (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Writings: Bibliography (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Writings: Bibliography (Box 6, Folder 53)
- Writings
  - Writings: Bibliography (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - Writings: Bibliography (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - Writings: Bibliography (Box 7, Folder 56)
  - Writings: Bibliography (Box 7, Folder 57)
  - Writings: Bibliography (Box 7, Folder 58)
  - Writings: Bibliography (Box 7, Folder 59)
  - Writings: Bibliography (Box 7, Folder 60)
  - Writings: Bibliography (Box 7, Folder 61)
  - Writings: Bibliography (Box 7, Folder 62)
  - Writings: Bibliography (Box 7, Folder 63)